&gt;&gt; Good morning, and welcome to
&gt;&gt; 早上好 欢迎了解
What's New in Cocoa Touch.
Cocoa Touch 新功能介绍
I'm Eliza, and I'll be joined
我是 Eliza
shortly on stage by Josh
等一下 Josh Shaffer 也会上台
Shaffer.
一起为大家讲解
And today, we have a ton of
今天 我们准备
great new APIs to tell you
给大家介绍一大批
about.
新的 API
We're going to start with some
首先 我们想为大家介绍一些
of the brand new productivity
在 iPad 和 iPhone 上使用的
APIs for iPad and iPhone.
全新的生产力 API
After that, we'll show you some
然后 我们会向大家展示
of the refinements to the User
在这些设备上的用户界面上
Interfaces on these devices, and
所做的改良
we'll talk about how you can get
我们还会讲解要如何
these effects in your own
把这些效果应用到
applications.
你们的 App 上面
And finally, we'll go through an
最后 我们还要介绍
assortment of additions and
针对 Cocoa Touch 上
improvements to existing APIs
已有的 API 的一系列
across Cocoa Touch.
新增与升级
So, the most important
iOS 中最重要的
productivity API in iOS 11, as
生产力 API
you heard in the keynote, is
大家在主旨演讲中已经听过了
Drag and Drop.
那就是拖拽与放置
This is an incredibly powerful
这是一个非常强大的
API.
API
Here's a video showing a couple
下面这个视频
of the things that it can do.
就展示了它的一些功能
So, I can pick up an item, drag
我可以选择一个东西
it around.
把它拖来拖去
I can tap to add additional
我可以通过轻轻点击来
items to the drag.
为拖拽添加目标
The system remains fully
在我进行拖拽动作的同时
interactive while my drags are
系统仍然保持互动
in progress, and I can even drag
我甚至可以
data between different
在不同应用之间
applications.
拖拽数据
So, we're really excited for you
我们很期待大家
guys to be adopting this API in
能够在你们的 App 中
your apps.
使用这项功能
And there are no fewer than four
本周还有至少
sessions this week, telling you
4 次演讲
all about how to do that.
为大家详细介绍这一功能
So, right now, I'm going to give
现在 我要为大家
you just a very brief overview
做一个非常简短的介绍
of some of the key components of
介绍这个 API 的一些
this API, beginning with
关键功能
enabling drags in your
首先 是在 App 中启用
application.
拖拽功能
So, suppose you have a custom
假如你有一个定制的 view
view with some sub-views, maybe
下面又有很多 sub-view
little icon like views, here,
比如像小图标一样的 view
that you want to make draggable.
你想让它们变得可拖拽
What you'll do, is create a UI
那么你就要建立一个
drag interaction, which is a new
UIDragInteraction
subclass of UI interaction.
这是 UI 交互下面的一个子类
And you'll attach it to the view
然后再把它附加到
that you want to allow the user
你希望能允许用户拖拽的
to drag.
View 上面
Now, a UI interaction is kind of
现在 一个 UI 交互
like a gesture recognizer.
就像一个动作识别器
You make one, you set a delegate
建立一个 UI 交互 为它设定一个委托
on it, you attach it to a view,
把它附加到一个 view 上
and then, the system takes care
剩下的事情就可以交给系统
of the rest.
去完成了
Your delegate will be called
你的委托会被
back to provide information.
唤起以提供信息
It's really quite easy to use.
使用起来真的很简单
So, here we would create a drag
我们可以生成一个
interaction object, assign
拖拽交互目标
ourself as a delegate, attach it
让自己成为委托
to this view.
把它附加到这个 view 上
And we would also, do the same
我们还可以
for the other views that we want
在其他可拖拽的 view 上
to make draggable.
重复同样的事
Now, the
现在
UIDragInteractionDelegate
UIDragInteractionDelegate
protocol gives you a ton of
协议给了你无数的
opportunity to customize what's
机会去利用拖拽
going on with this drag.
定制功能
The one thing you absolutely
你一定不要忘了
have to do, is provide the data
最重要的事
for the item that's being
要给被拖拽的目标
dragged.
提供数据
But apart from that, it's
除了这件事
entirely up to you.
其他的全取决于你
You can go with the system
你可以直接使用系统默认设置
defaults, or you can customize
或者你可以定制
all kinds of aspects of the
关于拖拽的一切
drag.
方面
Like, the lift animation, the
比如抬升的动画
previews, you can get callbacks
比如预览 你还可以随着触控光标在
as the touch moves around on the
屏幕上移动的时候得到回调
screen and do things in
并对其进行
response.
回应
It's entirely open to your
根据你的应用需求
application's needs.
可以灵活调整
So, the other major component of
显然 拖拽放置的
Drag and Drop, obviously, is the
另一个重要部分
drop component.
就是放置
And to enable that, you also use
启动这个功能 你需要
a new type of UI interaction
一个新型的 UI 交互
called the UIDropInteraction.
也就是 UIDropInteraction
And you attach that not to the
你不要把这个交互附加到
individual draggable views, but
各个可拖拽的 view 上 而是要
to the super view, the container
附加到 super view 上 也就是
that's going to receive items
准备接受放置的
dropped.
容器上
Once again, you set a delegate.
你需要再次设置一个委托
And once again, this delegate
同样地 这个委托
has the opportunity to do all
也可以进行各种各样的
kinds of customization.
定制
You can update your UI to make
你可以更新 UI
the other items get out of the
在拖拽中  清理一些其他
way as the drag moves around,
碍事的项目
show a visual indication of
或者用视觉化方式显示
where a drop would go, what
放置的目的地
would happen if the user were to
或者显示 如果用户放置了
drop.
会发生什么
You receive the data when the
进行放置时
drop is actually performed and
你会收到数据
you can update your model in
然后作为回应 你可以
response.
更新你的模型
And then, you can also customize
然后 你可以定制
all kinds of aspects of this
这个动画的
animation.
方方面面
You can customize the preview,
你可以定制预览
during the drop, the drop
放置过程中
animation itself, it's really
和放置动画本身
very powerful.
真的很好用
So, we're excited to see what
我们十分期待看到
you will create with all of the
你们利用这个功能
power of this feature.
大显身手
But to make it really easy to
为了让启动过程
get started, the system has
更加简单 系统还为
built-in support in a number of
很多现有的类
the existing classes that you're
提供内置支持
probably already using.
也许就有你正在用的
So, to get this going with
因此 要把这个功能用在
TableView, CollectionView, and
TableView CollectionView
the various Text and Web views,
和各种 Text 和 Web view 上面
there's very little work for you
其实需要你额外再去做的事
to do, in addition.
就很少了
One other useful piece of
这个系统上另一项
integration on this system, is
实用的整合
with UIPasteConfiguration.
就是使用 UIPasteConfiguration.
So, if your application already
如果你的应用
knows how to handle the paste
已经具有复制粘贴操作中的
part of a copy and paste
粘贴功能
operation, there's very little
那么你就不需要
extra work that you need to do
再做额外工作
to make that same view a drop
去让同一个 view 变成
target.
放置的目标了
So, here are the sessions on
这些就是关于拖拽放置
Drag and Drop.
的四场演讲
And the first one is
第一场是
introduction to Drag and Drop,
介绍拖拽与放置
right here, right after this
就在这里 这场演讲完
session.
就开始
And so, we really encourage you
因此 我们十分希望你们能留下
to stay for that.
看这场演讲
Tomorrow, we have Mastering Drag
明天的演讲是 熟练操作
and Drop.
拖拽与放置
And then, there's an entire
然后 有一整场演讲
session devoted to getting Drag
用来介绍如何
and Drop working with your table
把拖拽放置应用到
and collection views.
表格和集合 view 上
And a really important session
还有一场重要演讲
on the various ways that you can
介绍用拖拽和放置
manipulate data with your drags
操作数据的
and drops.
各种方式
There's actually a lot that you
大家可以做的事情
can do there, that's very
真的非常多
powerful.
非常好用
So, we encourage you to check
我们希望你们也能去听听
that out, as well.
那些讲座
All right.
好的
So, the other piece of our
我们对于 iPad 和 iPhone
productivity enhancements on
生产力的提高
iPad and iPhone is File
做的另一项工作
Management.
就是文件管理
We're introducing this wonderful
下面我们就介绍这个很棒的
view controller that allows your
View 控制功能 能够让
users to browse their documents,
用户在你们的 App 中
right in your app.
浏览文件
And this gives them access not
这不但能让他们
only to the local documents in
浏览 App 文件夹里的
your app's documents folder, but
本地文件
also, to documents stored on the
还能够浏览存储在
cloud in iCloud Drive, and also
iCloud Drive 上的云文件
in participating third party
还能够参与到第三方的
cloud storage services.
云存储服务
To make one of these.
要做到这一点
So, the class is called
这个类叫做
UIDocumentBrowserViewController.
UIDocumentBrowserViewController
And to make one, you pass it in
你需要把它传入
array of the file types that
你的 App 能够处理的
your app knows how to handle.
文件类型的数组中
That way, the user can't open a
这样一来 用户就不能
file using this API that your
用这个 API 打开
app doesn't know what to do
你的 App 所无法处理的
with.
文件了
And this class is actually quite
实际上 这个类也是
customizable.
可定制的
The appearance can be changed in
其外表可以变化成
a variety of ways.
不同形式
And you can also set different
你也可以设置
behaviors to occur as the user
让用户在浏览文件并选择时
navigates their files and
出现不同的
selects one.
呈现效果
As I mentioned, this gives you
我刚刚说过 这个功能
access both to local storage,
能让你浏览本地文件
and documents stored on the
也可以浏览云存储中的
cloud.
文件
And that comes with one
这就带来了一个
important caveat that's really
重要的警告
important to keep in mind.
需要牢记
Which is that you can no longer
也就是你不再能够
depend on your application being
指望你的 App
the only one touching a
是在某个时间访问某个特定文件的
particular file at a given time.
唯一的 App 了
So, it's really crucial to
因此 要协调文件入口
coordinate file access with
和你正在使用这个类访问的
documents that you're accessing
文件 这就非常重要了
And you can do that by using
要做到这一点
NSFileCoordinator, directly, or
你可以直接使用 NSFileCoordinator
by sub-classing UIDocument,
或者把 UI 文件向下分类
which builds in a lot of file
这可以为你提供很多
coordination behavior for you.
协调手段
To hear more about this class
想了解关于这个类
and other document based topics,
以及其他文件相关主题的更多信息
please check out this session on
请在周四参与这个
Thursday.
讲座
And now, I'm going to invite
下面我想请
Josh onstage, to talk us through
Josh 上台 为我们讲讲
some of the UI refinements in
iOS 11 中的一些 UI 的
iOS 11.
改良
[ Applause ]
［掌声］
&gt;&gt; All right.
&gt;&gt;好的
Thanks, Eliza.
谢谢 Eliza
So, there's a lot of really
在 iOS 11 中
great enhancements to
对于生产力 API 的增强
productivity APIs in iOS 11.
真的很了不起
But we've also got some really
但我们也有很多对于
great UI refinements, as well.
UI 的增强
And I want to talk through a
我想在此介绍一部分
bunch of them, starting with one
首先就是最引人注目的
of the most visible, which is
也就是在导航栏的顶部
the new large title at the top
那个新的巨大的
of the navigation bar.
标题
And this is the most visible
这是最引人注目的变化
change that you'll probably
你可能在开始使用 iOS 11 时
immediately notice, when you
立即就会注意到
start using iOS 11.
这一点
It includes this new large
包括这个新的巨大的
prominent title displayed at the
显示在顶部的
top.
标题
Along, with a new unified search
还有新的 集成的
field design that integrates it
整合在搜索栏中的
right in the bar.
搜索功能
So, while your content is
这样一来 你的内容在
scrolled to the top, you're
滚动到顶部时
going to be able to have easy
你就能轻而一举地
visibility of the large title
看到大标题
that tell exactly where you are,
知道自己在哪里
and easier access to the search
也很容易进入
field.
搜索栏
Because it's now pulled down a
因为这个部分
little bit farther than where it
被拉低了一些
usually would have been, in the
以前它的位置
past.
要更高
However, to maximize the area
但是 为了留出足够空间
available for displaying your
显示你的实际内容
actual content, as you start
当你开始向下滚动
scrolling, both of these will
搜索栏和标题
collapse in order to maximize
都会消失 下面的空间
the space below the bar, so you
就会变大
can see as much content as
这样一来你就能看到
possible.
尽可能多的内容
First, the search bar will
首先
collapse itself.
搜索栏会消失
And then, the large title will
然后大标题
scroll up under the bar, and
也会滚到上面去
you'll end up with a view that
这时你所看到的
looks very much like what you
就会和你在 iOS 11 之前的见到的
were used to, prior to iOS 11.
非常相似
Now, UINavigationController will
现在 UINavigationController 可以
automatically find the main
在你当下的视图控制中
primary content scroll view
自动找到
inside of your currently visible
滚动视图中
view controller.
最主要的内容
And track its content offset to
并跟踪它偏移量
make sure that it can do this on
确保它可以按你的意思
your behalf.
来做这件事
So, in most cases, there's
因此 在大多数情况下
actually not a lot of work that
你需要为了实现这个功能
you need to do, in order to
而去做的事情
adopt that.
其实并不多
Enabling all this behavior is
实现上述所有功能
actually really straightforward.
其实很简单
There's one new property on
在 UINavigationBar 中
UINavigationBar called
有一个新属性
prefersLargeTitle.
叫做 prefersLargeTitle
And if you just set that to yes,
如果在这项中选择 yes
you're going to get the large
就会有大号
title appearance and
标题的显示
NavigationController will
NavigationController
automatically do that tracking
就会自动展开追踪
that we just talked about.
就像我们刚才说过的那样
Finding your scroll view,
找到你的滚动视图
tracking its offset, and
追踪偏移量
handling the shrinking.
控制缩放
Now, the second thing is a new
接下来 第二件事就是
property on UINavigationItem.
UINavigationItem 中的新属性
And this lets you control the
这会让你在导航层级的
appearance of the large title
每一个层级中
for every level of your
能够控制
navigation hierarchy.
大标题的外观
So, not every level, as you're
在你把视图控制器放在 Navstack 上时
pushing view controllers onto
并不是每一个层级
the Navstack, needs to display
都需要显示
the large title.
大标题
And in fact, many often do not.
实际上 很多都不需要
So, you can control at each
因此你可以使用这个导航属性
level using this navigation item
控制每一个层级
property, whether the large
是否需要大标题
title, or the older more small
还是需要以前那种
traditional style is what you'll
传统的更小的标题
see at any given point.
在什么时候出现哪一种
Adopting the searchController
使用 searchController
appearance is also, really easy.
外观也非常非常容易
You can just use this new
你可以使用这个新的
searchController property, in
searchController 属性
order to get that new appearance
来获得新的外观
and all the new behaviors.
以及所有新的行为
Now, traditionally in the past,
在过去
you would have taken your
你可能需要把导航栏
navigation bar and probably
作为内容的一部分
included it as part of your
也许你需要
content, maybe made it the table
把它做成你的
header view for your
UITableView 的
UITableView.
顶部视图
Now, instead of doing that,
现在不需要了
because the new appearance looks
因为新的外观看起来
more like it's part of the bar,
就好像是导航栏的一部分
you can just use this property
你可以使用这个属性
and you'll get all those
就能够获得所有的
behaviors.
行为了
Now generally, the first view on
一般来说
your navigation stack is the
只有在导航层级的
only one that you would use the
第一层才会用到
large title for.
大标题
This is a general bit of
在设计 App 指南中
guidance for designing your apps
一般都会这样讲
to use these large titles.
这样使用大标题
Then, as you push in to a second
然后 推向第二层视图
level view and keep navigating
并继续向下导航
deeper, you'd usually use the
你往往会使用
more smaller traditional size.
更小的字体
This is a great starting point
这是设计的良好开端
for your designs, but as we just
但正如我们之前提到的
mentioned, it is fully under
一切全凭你通过 API 控制
your control via the API, so you
因此你可以
can do the right thing for your
为你的 App 选择你认为合适的
app.
显示方式
And in fact, if you look through
实际上 如果你看一看
some of ours, you'll find that
我们的设计 你会发现
Mail, for instance, uses the
比如电子邮件
large title at the first two
就在前两个层级
levels.
使用了大标题
You'll also notice that the
你可能还注意到了
refresh control is now
刷新控制现在
integrated in this new, single,
也整合到了这个新的 单一的
large title.
大标题下面
Now, if you use a UI refresh
如果你在 App 中使用
control in your app to get your
UI 刷新控制
Pull to Refresh behavior, this
以达到下拉刷新效果
will actually happen
这一点现在就会
automatically.
自动进行了
So, there's no additional work
因此你也就不需要
you have to do to get that
付出额外劳动
visual integration with the bar.
去做导航栏的视觉整合工作了
One important thing to note
关于这些大标题
about these large titles and the
和搜索栏 重要的一点是
bar is that they're actually
他们实际上是
part of the navigation bar, not
导航栏的一部分
part of your content view.
而不是内容视图的一部分
As a result, the navigation bar
这样一来 导航栏本身
itself, is actually quite a bit
就会比之前
taller than you might normally
你所习惯的
be used to from previous
iOS 版本
releases of iOS.
要高一些
And in fact, it can now change
实际上 现在它的高度在
height as the content scrolls.
内容滚动时会变化
As you can see, it's larger
如你所见
while the large title is
大标题出现的时候
visible.
它就大一点
And then, as the user scrolls
而当用户向上滚动
and the large title disappears,
大标题消失后
the navigation bar takes on a
导航栏的高度就会变得
more traditional height as you
更像以前
would normally be used to.
大家所习惯的那样
Now, you might initially be
你可能会觉得
concerned that this could be
担心这一功能
complicated to deal with.
会很复杂
But the teams have been working
但我们的团队
really hard to make sure that
十分努力地工作
this is as easy as possible to
确保这一点尽可能地简单
deal with, in your apps.
在你的 App 中得以实现
And in most cases, it can
在大多数情况下
actually be handled
这一点实际上是
automatically on your behalf,
自动替你完成的
with no additional work.
无需付出更多工作
UINavigationController does a
UINavigationController
lot of this for you.
已经替你完成了
Now, to make it easier, though,
不过 为了让这一切更简单
to find out as these bars change
为了把握导航栏高度的变化
height, there's a new property
在 UIView 中还有一个新的属性
on UIView, that's actually
这个新属性也非常好用
really generally useful and can
并且可以应用在
apply across your entire
你的 App 中的
application.
各个地方
And that's the new safeAreaInset
它就是全新的 safeAreaInset
property.
属性
So, safeAreaInset lets you know
safeAreaInset 能够让你知道
the area of your content that is
内容的区域是否
visible underneath anything that
会被导航栏
might be obscured by bars.
遮挡
So, you can reliably and easily
这样一来 你就可以放心地
place your content in the area
把内容放在
that will be visible and not
能够显示出来
obstructed by any of these other
而且不会被其他的系统 UI
system UIs, like the bar at the
比如在顶部和底部的导航栏
top and bottom.
所阻挡了
Now, with this information, you
知道了这一点
can easily do that layout.
你就能够轻松完成布局了
And as the bar changes height
用户上下滚动时
while the user scrolls, the
导航栏高度会变化
safeAreaInset will grow so that
safeAreaInset 也会相应变化
you can easily stay below the
你就能轻松避开
bar.
导航栏了
Now, if your view is overlapped
而如果你的视图与
by a toolbar or a tab bar on the
底部的工具栏
bottom, you're going to find
或是点击栏发生重合
that the safeAreaInset has a
safeAreaInset 就会在底部
value for its bottom, as well.
派上用场了
So that you can be sure that you
你也就能确认
know the exact area, top and
所有的区域
bottom, that you can safely
无论顶部还是底部
display content in.
然后放心地放置内容了
The safeAreaInsets are really
safeAreaInsets 的使用
easy to access, too.
也十分容易
So, there's three new properties
在 UIView 中
on UIView that make it easy to
有三个新属性
use this.
让使用它更容易
The first is the
第一个是
safeAreaLayoutGuide.
safeAreaLayoutGuide
Now, with safeAreaLayoutGuide,
有了 safeAreaLayoutGuide,
you can easily integrate safe
你就可以轻易把安全区域
areas with all of your auto
与你的自动分层代码
layout code.
整合起来
So, you can set up constraints
你可以对这个 layout guide
against this layout guide to
进行限制
position all of your content
以便把你的内容
within the safe area.
放进安全区
Now, if you're performing layout
如果你选择手动调整布局
manually, you may actually just
那么你需要读取
want to read the current safe
某个时间点的
area values for a particular
当下的安全区的数值
And you can do that with the
你可以使用
safeAreaInsets property.
safeAreaInsets 属性来完成这一点
Now, this is in the coordinate
这是和你的视图的空间
space of your view, so it's
相协调的 因此
really easy to use to position
很容易就能把内容
your content exactly where you
精确地放置在你想要的
want.
地方
Now, of course, if you're doing
当然 如果你在用手动方式
manual layout, you'll also need
调整布局 那么你还需要知道
to know when that changes.
什么时候会产生变化
And so, you can override the
因此 你可以覆盖
safeAreaInsetsDidChange property
safeAreaInsetsDidChange 属性
to find out when it changes and
发现什么时候发生了变化
adjust your layout.
并调整布局
Now, there's a lot of things,
现在很多事情
because this is integrated
因为整合到了
throughout UIKit, that could be
UIKit 里面
handled automatically for you,
可以自动为你实现
that previously would have been
之前实现起来会
more difficult.
更困难的事
For instance, UIScrollView can
举例来说 UIScrollView
automatically include the
可以自动涵盖
safeAreaInsets as additional
safeAreaInsets 让它成为在
scrollable padding at the top
视图顶部和底部
and bottom of your views.
可滚动的填充
So, that even if they're
就算他们与导航栏发生负重叠
underlapping the bars, you can
你也可以确信
be sure that your content can
你的内容总是会
always be scrolled into view.
被滚动到视图里面
Now, in previous releases,
在之前的版本中
UINavigationController tried to
UINavigationController 曾经试图
handle some of this on your
代替开发者
behalf by calculating the
以计算导航栏重叠的方式
overlap of the bars.
完成这些任务
And then, setting a value on the
然后
contentInset property for your
为 UIScrollView 中的
UIScrollView.
contentInset 属性设定数值
Now, you may have noticed that
你也许注意到了
if you ever tried to set your
如果你想要为
own contentInset for the
UIScrollView
UIScrollView, because you'd end
设定你自己的 contentInset 数值
up fighting with
结果却与 NavigationController
NavigationController over who
发生了矛盾
owned that current value at a
因为不能决定在某一既定时间
given time.
谁拥有当前的数值
In iOS 11, that conflict is
在 iOS 11 中
gone, because
这个矛盾消失了
UINavigationController no longer
因为 UINavigationController
has to set the contentInset
不再必须设定 contentInset
property.
属性了
ScrollView can set it on its own
ScrollView 可以自己设定了
behalf, by just looking at the
只需看一下
safeAreaInsets, leaving the
safeAreaInsets
actual value of contentInset to
把 contentInset 的真正数值
be owned by you, for your
为你所有
application needs.
取决于你的 App 的需要
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, UIScrollView tries to do the
UIScrollView 会尽力去
right thing, automatically, as
自动完成正确的操作
much as possible for this case.
尽可能地去完成
But it's not always possible, of
但当然 这并不总是可能的
course, to get it right 100% of
不总是能百分之百地
the time.
完成任务
And we know some of your apps
我们知道 有一些 App
have different needs.
有不同的需求
So, to help make sure that you
因此 为了保证
can always have the right
你总能获得正确的
behavior, we have a new property
行为 我们设计了一个
on UIScrollView that gives you
UIScrollView 上的新属性
full control over how ScrollView
让你能完全掌控 ScrollView
interprets these safeAreaInsets.
对 safeAreaInsets 的解读
So, with this, you can tell it
有了这个 你就能决定
whether it should automatically
它是否应该自动应用插入
apply the insets, or just ignore
或者完全地把它们
them, entirely.
忽视掉
So, that you can do the right
这样一来 你就可以
thing for your app, if it
随心所欲地处理你的 App
happens to be the case that the
即便在自动行为
automatic behavior isn't exactly
不是你想要的情况下
what you want.
也可以这样了
And if you want to find out
如果你想知道
exactly what has happened, as
有关 ScrollView 的
far as the ScrollView is
具体情况
concerned, you can look at one
你可以利用一个
new property that can give you
新的属性 它能够
the current value of what it has
根据 safeAreaInsets
computed from safeAreaInsets,
计算出的数值
plus the sum of an contentInsets
还有你自己使用
that you have set, yourself with
AdjustedContentInset 属性设置的
the adjustedContentInset
contentInset 的数量
property.
你可以看到
much space the ScrollView thinks
ScrollView 认为自己需要
it needs to have for scrollable
多少空间
padding.
来进行可滚动的填充
So, so far, we've focused a lot
目前为止 我们一直在讲
on bars.
导航栏
But there's also some other
但对于 UI 其他部分
refinements to other parts of
也有一些改良
You'll find that UITableViews
你会发现 系统各处的
across the system, how have a
UITalbeView 现在都有了一个
new unified swipe delete
新的 统一的轻扫删除
implementation that feels just
操作 这和你习惯的
like what you're used to from
Mail App 中的操作
the Mail app.
是一模一样的
It includes support for multiple
包括支持多重动作
actions on both the left and
向左和向右轻扫
right swipes, as well as single
也包括默认的
gesture activation of the
单一动作
default one, with a full gesture
与整个 TableView
across the entire TableView.
中的全指令
It's also really easy to use in
要把它应用在你的 App 中
your apps, as well.
也很简单
So, with the new
利用新的
UIContextualAction class, you
UIContextualAction 类
can specify the actions that you
你可以指定出
want to be able to display in
你想要在 TableView 中
the TableView's rows.
展示的动作
Just providing the style that
只需要提供你想要它们
you'd like them to appear with,
出现的姿态
and the title of the action, and
和动作的名称
a block to invoke when they
以及适时激活它们的
should be run.
block 就可以了
And then, with the new
然后 利用新的
UISwipeActionConfiguration
UISwipeActionConfiguration
class, you can group together
类你可以把这些动作
multiple of these contextual
集合起来
actions to display on the left
在每一行的左侧
and right side of individual
或者右侧显示出来
And you can also specify whether
你还可以指定
the first one should
是否要在整行中
automatically be invoked when a
出现全指令时
full gesture occurs across the
激活第一个
entire row.
动作
Yeah, it's very cool.
是的 这很酷
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
We do actually use this, now,
现在 我们可以在整个系统中
across the system.
用上这些
You'll find more actions in many
你会在更多的地方
more places than before.
发现更多的动作指令了
But do keep in mind, though,
不过不要忘了
when you're using it, that any
使用它的时候
actions that you put in the rows
你放在轻扫手势后面的
behind the swipe actions will be
动作会比较
hard to discover than
难以发现
something's that's visually
这是相对于那些在你的 App 中
prominent in your application.
视觉效果突出的动作来说的
So, definitely use it as an
所以 你当然可以使用这个功能
accelerator, but probably don't
锦上添花 但不要把它
make it the only way to perform
当作行使某个动作的
a particular action.
唯一的方式
So, outside of that, we've also
在那之外 我们还
given you more control over the
给予你在 UITableView 里
placement of separators in your
放置分割线
UITableView.
的更多控制权
So, there's a new property on
UITalbeView 中
UITableView that lets you
有一个新属性 让你能够
control how separatorInsets that
掌控你在 TableView 中
you set on the TableView are
设置的 separatorInsets
interpreted.
如何被解读
You can indicate that they are
你可以把它们
absolute values so they're
定义成绝对值
relative from the edge of the
这样一来 它们就与单元格边缘
cell.
相对
Or you can indicate that they're
你也可以把它们
meant to be deltas, offset from
定义成差值
where the TableView would have
它们就会分支出来
otherwise placed the
如果你没有明确指定
separatorInsets had you not
TableView 就会把 separatorInsets
specified anything.
放置在那些地方
This makes it a lot easier to
这会让你很容易地
make sure that your separators
就能确定 分割线
end at exactly where you want
就在你希望的位置
them.
终止
Regardless of the device that
无论你使用什么样的设备
you're running on or the size
或者你正在运行的
class that you're currently
类的大小
running in.
都无所谓
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, there's a ton of new UI
有很多的新的
refinements.
UI 的改良
And there's a whole session that
之后会有一整场演讲
can tell you about this and many
详细阐述这些
more.
以及更多
It's the Updating Your App for
那就是为 iOS 11
iOS 11 session.
升级你的 App
So, you should definitely check
因此 大家一定要
that out.
去听那场演讲
And to give you some ideas on
此外 为了给大家讲解
the thinking behind the design
一部分升级
of some of these new updates and
背后的想法
how you can best integrate them
以及建议大家如何把它们
into your apps, definitely also,
整合到你们的 App 中
check out the design session,
请一定去听设计演讲
Design Studio Shorts 2, later
Design Studio Shorts 2
this week, as well.
就在本周晚些时候进行
So, with that, I'll hand things
现在 我要把舞台
back to Eliza to tell you about
交还给 Eliza 请她告诉大家
some more API enhancements
更多的 Cocoa Touch
around Cocoa Touch.
API 增强方面的信息
Thanks.
谢谢
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
All right.
好的
I'd like to start with some of
我想先讲一下
the new APIs in Swift 4 and
Swift 4 和 Foundation 中的
Foundation.
新 API
So, there's actually a lot of
有很多很多
really exciting additions to
非常令人振奋的东西被添加到
Swift 4.
Swift 4 上
And I'm only going to cover two
我在此只能
things, now.
讲两个
The first is archiving Swift
首先是把 Swift
native types.
的原生类型归档
So, if you've attempted to use
如果你打算使用
Swift 4 native types like
Swift 4 的原生类型
enumerations and structs with
比如列举和结构
code that needs to participate
使用需要参与的代码
in, for example, NSCoding,
比如 NSCoding
you'll have found that this has
你会发现
been historically quite
以前这是比较
difficult to do.
难以实现的
Swift 4 solves that problem with
Swift 4 用一项新的
the introduction of a new
可编码的协议
Codable protocol.
解决了这个问题
And as long as the underlying
只要你的列举中的
types in your enumerations and
下层类型具有结构
structs, are themselves codable,
而且是可编码的
all you have to do to adopt this
那么你只需
is declare conformance to the
对协议声明一致
protocol.
就可以了
And then, Swift handles the
其余的交给 Swift
rest.
就行了
So, that allows these native
这就让这些原生
types to participate easily in
类型可以很容易地加入
NSCoding.
NSCoding
And Foundation has also added
Foundation 同样也添加了
support for archiving to JSON
对于 JSON 归档和
and property lists.
属性列表的支持
Another really exciting edition
对于 Swift 4 的另一项
to Swift 4 is the new KeyPath
令人欣喜的改版是新的 KeyPath 类型
type, and a literal syntax, and
和一个新的 literal syntax
getters and setters that
以及能够对其做出反应的
correspond to it.
getter 和 setter
So, in the past, you specified
在过去 你只能在代码中
KeyPaths by hardcoding a String
硬编码一个 String
in your code, which as a result,
来指出 KeyPaths
couldn't be, if you had a typo
这样做的结果就是
in it, it wouldn't be found at
如果你打错了一个字母 在编译中
compile time.
就找不到它了
Now, there's a new literal
现在 有了新的
syntax, this /, that allows you
literal syntax 这个
to construct a KeyPath, and this
能够让你建立一个 KeyPath
is a strongly typed object.
这是一个强类型对象
So, if I have a presenter
那么 假设我有一个 presenter 对象
object, for example, that has a
这个对象有一些属性
couple properties, a
一个 copresenter
copresenter, which is another
也就是另一个 presenter
presenter, and a name.
和一个名字
I can construct a KeyPath object
我可以建立一个 KeyPath 对象
representing my copresenter's
来代表我的 presenter 的
name.
名字
And then, I can use this new
然后 我可以用这个新的
square bracket getter notation
方括号 getter 记号
to access that property on one
进入我的一个 presenter
of my presenter objects.
对象的属性
So, in this case, accessing it
在这个例子中
on an object representing me
进入一个代表我的对象
would return the String Josh.
会返回 Josh 这个 String
You can also forego making the
你还可以放弃
KeyPath object as a separate
制作 KeyPath 对象
step and just use the literal
作为独立的步骤
syntax in the getter.
而只在 getter 中使用 literal syntax
And take advantage of Swift's
并利用 Swift 的
type inference, to leave off the
类型推断 放弃类型
type, if you do it that way.
如果你那样做的话
So, this is very cool.
这是非常酷的
And Foundation has taken it one
至于 Foundation 则更进了一步
step further by introducing an
把通过这些 KeyPath
updated way of using KVO with
使用 KVO 的方式
these KeyPaths.
做了一个更新
So, this is a picture of what
这张图展示的是
you used to have to do to
在此之前你为了
observe changes to a property on
观察你的对象的一个属性的改变
one of your objects.
要做的事
It was a little bit involved.
这有点麻烦
You had to override a method.
你必须要覆盖一个 method
And because your Superclass
因为你的 Superclass
might also override that method,
可能也要覆盖这个 method
you had to use a context pointer
你必须得用 context pointer
to disambiguate which one of you
来指明到底是谁
is getting it at any given time.
在某个时间占据主导
And it was quite difficult to
要把它弄对
get right.
并不容易
So, new in iOS 11, we have
而现在 在新的 iOS 11 里
block-based KVO.
我们有了基于 block 的 KVO
We're really excited about it.
我们觉得这很棒
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
If I want to observe the changes
如果我想要查看我的
to my copresenter, I'm not sure
copresenter 的改动
why I would, since it never
虽然它似乎从未改动过
seems to change, I can do so by
我只需要
simply setting a block and
设置一个 block
observing one of these KeyPaths
然后用一个 literal syntax
using a literal syntax.
查看其中一个 KeyPath 就可以了
So, that's very cool.
这是非常酷的
There's a lot of new topics in
在 Foundation 中有很多新的
Foundation.
主题
And please check out their
欢迎去看相关的演讲
related session, on Wednesday.
星期三开始
Okay, deferring system gestures.
好 下面是延迟系统手势
And this is a funny case.
这是个很有趣的例子
So, if you have an app that
如果你有一个 App
maybe, shows some content, and
它显示了一些内容
shows its status bar, the user
显示了状态栏
can swipe down from the top to
用户可以从顶部向下轻扫
bring in the notification
调出通知中心
However, if you hid your status
但是如果你把状态栏隐藏起来
bar and the user swipes down
用户再从顶部向下轻扫
from the top, they'll instead
他们就会看到
see this tab UI.
这个点击 UI
And in that case, your app will
这样一来 你的 App 就会
actually receive the touches
自动接收
that are originating near the
屏幕顶部附近
top of the screen.
生成的点击
Now, we did this in iOS 5, when
我们在 iOS 5 中这样做过
we introduced the Notification
当时我们给大家带来了
Center.
通知中心
Because we wanted to make sure
因为我们希望确定
that apps that might need to see
App 能够保证
touches near the edges of the
屏幕边缘附近的点击
screen, could do so.
是有效的
And we took the presence or
我们还用状态栏
absence of the status bar as an
是否显示
indication of whether your app
来辨别你的 App
fell in that category.
是否属于这一类型
So, then in iOS 7, we introduced
然后在 iOS 7 里
the Control Center with a swipe
我们又推出了底部向上轻扫
up from the bottom.
呼出控制中心
If your app hid its status bar,
如果你的 App 隐藏了状态栏
we used the same rule and we
我们会应用同样的法则
would show the tab instead of
显示出点击 UI
the control center.
而不是控制中心
Now, that made a little bit less
现在 这样做的目的
sense, because the status bar is
其实不是很有意义
at the top of the screen, not
因为状态栏是在屏幕顶部
the bottom.
不是底部
And so, the presence or absence
那么状态栏
of the status bar shouldn't
显示与否就不应该
really tell us very much about
意味着你的 App
what your app needs to see, in
在屏幕底部
terms of touches near the
是否需要确保
bottom.
点击有效
So, the other problem with the
现在这种情况
status quo, here, is that your
还有一个问题
users really want, when they
那就是用户在
swipe near the edge of the
屏幕边缘轻扫时
screen, to see the system UIs
他们很想看到系统 UI
components appear.
组件的出现
That's what they expect to have
他们希望能实现
happen.
这一点
So, unless your app actually
因此除非你的 App
needs to get access to the
需要利用到边缘
touches near the edge, it's a
附近的触碰
better user experience to allow
否则对于用户体验更好的
those notifications that are in
方式是让控制中心的
Control Center to simply appear
通知就这样
right away.
直接出现
So, in iOS 11, we're allowing
因此 在 iOS 11 里
you to make this explicit by
我们会允许你实现这一点
adding this new
通过添加这个新的
preferredScreenEdgesForDeferring
preferredScreenEdgesForDeferring
System Gestures method.
系统手势 method
If you override it in your
如果你在
viewControllers, you can return
viewControllers 中覆盖它
a UIRectEdge, which is a
你可以返回一个 UIRectEdge
collection of different edges.
这是不同边缘的集合
And we strongly encourage you to
我们极力推荐你
only return edges that you want
仅仅退回那些
to protect from system gestures.
你希望不让系统手势干扰的边缘
If you really need to see
如果你真的需要确保
touches that are right on that
在边缘位置的
edge of the screen.
点击生效的话
Because it will be a better
因为用户体验更好的方式
experience for you users to just
就是让系统手势
allow the system gestures to
以最简单的方式
happen as they normally would.
直接出现
All right.
好了
So, another topic where we've
另外一个我们
made some improvements, is Auto
加以改进的主题
Layout.
是 Auto Layout
And in particular, the
特别是 Auto Layout
interaction of Auto Layout and
和 Scroll View
Scroll Views.
之间的交互
So, Scroll Views pose kind of a
因为 Scroll Views 对
challenge for Auto Layout,
Auto Layout 其实是一种挑战
because they represent two
因为他们代表了两种
different coordinate systems
不同的坐标系
mushed into one.
揉到一起
You have the frame of the Scroll
你有 Scroll View 的框架
View, and then, you have the
然后 你又有了
coordinate system of its
其内容的坐标系
Which is often larger than the
后者又时常比
Scroll View, and is almost
Scroll View 要大 而且几乎总是
always offset relative to the
与 Scroll View 的源
Scroll View's origin.
产生偏移量
So, when you're composing your
因此在你为 Scroll View
constraints for Scroll Views,
施加约束的时候
Scroll View has a lot of
Scroll View 总有很多
know-how kind of built in, where
内置的技巧
it guesses what you probably
它会猜测你想要
meant.
做什么
And it tries to do the right
它会根据你所
thing based on the constraints
设置的约束来尽力
that you're composing.
去做正确的事
But in iOS 11, we're allowing
但在 iOS 11 中 我们会允许
you to make it really clear what
你把自己的意思表达地
you mean and be completely
非常清楚
explicit about it, by
完全明确
introducing two new Layout
因为我们在 Scroll View 上
guides on Scroll View.
推出了两个新的 Layout guide
A contentLayoutGuide and a
一个是 contentLayoutGuide
frameLayoutGuide.
另一个是 frameLayoutGuide
So, now you can construct
现在你可以设置
constraints that specifically
明确代表一个坐标系
represent one of these
或者另一个坐标系
coordinate systems or the other.
的约束了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, this allows you to do
这会让你能够
something really easily, that
省很多力气
used to be hard.
而过去这很麻烦
So, sometimes when you have a
有时你有一个
Scroll View and you have content
Scroll View 然后你有
that can zoom in and out.
可以大小缩放的内容
You want the content to come to
你希望能够在缩放时
rest in the center of the Scroll
让内容在
View as you're zooming out on
Scroll View 中心位置
it.
停止
Now, Josh and I, a couple of
Josh 与我在几年前
years ago, spent one-third of
在一场 WWDC 讲座上用了
the WWDC presentation explaining
三分之一的时间来解释
how you could get this effect in
你要如何在 Scroll View 中
your Scroll Views.
实现这个效果
And up until recently, it was
直到最近
actually really hard to do it
使用 Auto Layout 都很难
with Auto Layout.
做到这一点
But now, you can do it in two
但现在 你只需两行代码
lines of code.
就能实现了
All you need to do is set the
你只需要在 imageView 中
centerXAnchor of the imageView,
设置 centerXAnchor
or whatever the content of your
或者你的 Scroll View 的
Scroll View is, equal to the
任何内容和
contentLayoutGuide's
contentLayoutGuide 的
centerXAnchor.
centerXAnchor 对等就行
And then, you would do the same
然后你需要在
thing in the Y coordinate.
Y 轴上做同样的事
And then, this will just happen.
然后就大功告成
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
All right.
好了
So, Dynamic Type.
下面是 Dynamic Type
Now, dynamic type is a really
dynamic type 是 iOS 上一个
important feature on iOS.
很重要的特性
And here's a picture of a whole
这幅图显示的是
bunch of different dynamic type
大量不同的 dynamic type 尺寸
sizes that the user may
用户可以设置它们
configure, and how we're
我们可以在自己的
handling it in our own Calendar
Calendar App 里
app.
控制它
So, here's a small setting for
这是一个小的
dynamic type.
dynamic type
Larger. Larger.
变大 变大
Very large.
变得很大
And there even are larger
更大的 dynamic type 尺寸
accessibility dynamic type sizes
都可以通过选择
that can be selected.
来实现
So, this can pose a challenge in
这就以多种形式
a number of ways to support in
对你的 App 的支持
your applications.
形成了挑战
But for users who have chosen a
但对于那些选择了非标准
nonstandard dynamic type size,
dynamic type 尺寸的用户来说
it's a really bad user
如果你的 App 不支持
experience if your app doesn't
他们的选择
participate or honor their
那么这用户体验
selection.
就很差了
So, we've made a few
我们做了一些改进
improvements to make it easier
让你在你的 App 里
to do this correctly in your
做对这件事变得
applications.
更容易
And the first one has to do with
第一件事就是控制
sizing your text.
文本的尺寸
So, suppose you have a 16-point
假如你把 16 号字
font that you're using for the
作为标准字体的尺寸
How do you decide what font to
那么你该如何决定
use if the user has a
用户选择非标准 dynamic type 的时候
nonstandard dynamic type
该用到哪一种
selection?
字号呢
The old way of doing this was
要做到这一点 以前的办法
you could ask UIFont for the
是让 UIFont 对某种文本格式
preferred font for a given text
给出偏好的字号
And there's a number of text
有很多文本格式
styles, Body, Title, a variety
字体 标题
of them you can look up.
有很多供你查看
And this was pretty good,
这很好
because it would get you a good
因为它可以为你
font for the appropriate place
在 App 里的适当位置
in your application.
提供合适的字体
But it was a little inflexible,
但这有点不自由
because what if you needed a
因为你无法得到一个
custom font?
定制的字体
This is just going to give you
它每次只能给你
the system font, every time.
系统字体
What if you wanted to use a
如果你想在特定情况下
Monospace Number font in some
使用 Monospace Number 字体
particular case?
又该怎么办呢
Or just some font that, you
或者是那些
know, matched your branding a
更搭配你品牌的
little bit better.
那些字体
In iOS 11, we're introducing a
在 iOS 11 里 我们推出了
new class that solves this
一个新的类解决了这个问题
problem, called UIFontMetrics.
那就是 UIFontMetrics.
And the way you use it, is you
使用它的方法
create a FontMetrics object for
就是对于你感兴趣的文本格式
the text style that you're
建立一个 FontMetrics
interested in.
对象
You then, choose any font you
然后 选择任何你想要的字体
want, sized for the standard
尺寸就是标准的
dynamic type size.
dynamic type 尺寸
And then, you can ask the
然后 你可以让
FontMetrics object to scale that
FontMetrics 对象
font given the user's current
在用户当前设定的基础上 测量那个
settings.
字体
And that gets you back a font,
这让你得到一个字体
any font you want, at the
任何你所需要的字体
appropriate size to display.
大小正合适
Yeah, this is really cool.
是的 这非常酷
So, just that, alone, doesn't
但只有这一点
completely solve the problem,
还不足以完全解决问题
because imagine you have like a
假设你需要一个
custom button, or maybe a custom
定制的按键 或者一个定制的
bar.
栏
And you're putting some text
然后要往里面放一些
inside it.
文本
How tall do you want to make
你打算把那个按键的高度设定成
that button?
多少呢
If the user has a nonstandard
如果用户使用了非标准的
dynamic type setting, it might
dynamic type 设置 它就可能
overrun the height that you've
覆盖掉你所设置的
made available.
那个高度
So, UIFontMetrics has solved
UIFontMetrics 解决了
this problem, as well, by
这个问题 办法就是
allowing you to scale arbitrary
允许你测量任意的
layout values.
Layout 值
So, you create, once again, a
你要再次建立一个
FontMetrics object.
FontMetrics 对象
You choose a height that would
选择一个适合
look good at the standard
标准 dynamic type 尺寸的
dynamic type size, and then you
高度 然后你可以
can scale it based on the user's
根据用户的当前设定
current settings.
测量它
So, this is super useful for
这对于你的字体尺寸和 layout 来说
your font sizing and layout.
是非常好用的
Now, we also have an addition to
我们还为 Auto Layout
Auto Layout to support dynamic
添加了特性 让它支持
type, which we're pretty excited
dynamic type 我们对此也很兴奋
Suppose that I have two labels
假如我有两个商标
with different fonts, maybe,
字体不同 也许
laid out vertically.
垂直分布
And I've chosen a baseline to
我选择了一个基线
baseline spacing that looks good
到基线的间隔 在这个字体大小下面
at this font size.
看起来很合适
Now, my user might have chosen a
我的用户可能选择了
larger or a smaller dynamic type
更大或更小的 dynamic type
size.
尺寸
And as a result, the spacing
结果就让间隔
might actually look quite a bit
变得太近
too tight or too loose.
或者太远了
So, with Auto Layout, there's
现在 用 Auto Layout
now a solution for this problem,
可以解决这个问题
which is that we're exposing a
那就是我们为获取
way to access the system
系统推荐的间隔
recommended spacing.
提供了办法
And you do this by, first of
要做到这一点 首先
all, there's two ingredients.
有两个要素
You need to be doing baseline to
你需要做基线到基线间隔
baseline spacing, in order to
用这种方式来
inform Auto Layout that it
告诉 Auto Layout
should take font sizes into
它应该考虑字体的大小
So, I would make a topAnchor
我可能会用 topLabel 里的 topAnchor
using the lastBaselineAnchor of
lastBaselineAnchor 制作一个
my topLabel, and a bottomAnchor
topAnchor 再用 bottomLabel 里的
using the firstBaselineAnchor of
firstBaselineAnchor 制作一个
my bottomLabel.
bottomAnchor
And then, I would use the new
然后我会用新的
constraintEqualToSystemSpacing
constraintEqualToSystemSpacing
below method to ask Auto Layout
below method 来让 Auto Layout
to choose a value that will look
选择一个看上去合适的值
good, given the font sizes that
前提是知道被显示的
are being displayed.
字体的大小
And that will cause the text to
那会让文本去适应
adjust, so that's it's visually
这会让所有不同的
pleasing at all of the different
dynamic type 的尺寸
dynamic type sizes.
看上去都很舒服
And this works with the Visual
这同样适用于
Format Language, as well.
Visual Format Language
Again, we have the same two
我们有同样的两种
ingredients.
要素
We have the system spacing,
第一个是系统间隔
which is provided by the dashes
这是由
in my Visual Format String, and
我的 Visual Format String 的 dash 提供的
then, a new baseline to baseline
其次是一个新的基线到基线的
option to pass.
选项
So, that the Auto Layout system
这样一来 Auto Layout 系统
will know to do this work for
就会明白 替你完成这些工作了
you.
这对 UIStackView 也一样
UIStackView, again, passing
只要提供同样的
those same two options.
两个选项就行
So, to find out more about
要了解更多的使用 dynamic type
building your apps with dynamic
构建 App 的方法
type, please check out this
欢迎去参加
associated session, on Friday.
在周五举行的相关演讲
A lot of good content, here.
有很多精彩内容
All right.
好了
Password Autofill.
下面是 Password Autofill
This is my very favorite new
这是在今年推出的新 API 里面
API, that we're introducing,
我最喜欢的一个
this year.
我真的觉得它很棒
Some of you may have experienced
你们中有些人也许经历过
a workflow similar to this.
类似的 workflow
This is my standard workflow
这是我在登录 web service 的时候
when I sign up for a web
所采用的标准 workflow
service.
比如我登录了某种
some kind.
web service
I allow Safari to suggest a
我允许 Safari 建议
password, which I dutifully
密码 然后我接受了它
accept.
这是一个很棒的强密码
I would never want type in a
我永远也不想输入一遍
Then, the service says, ''Hey,
然后这个 service 会说
download our app.'' And so, I
来吧 下载我们的 App 吧
do.
我照做了
I launch the app, and I'm
我打开这个 App
immediately presented with this
立即就看到了这个
password entry field.
密码输入界面
And of course, I've saved this
当然我在 iCloud 钥匙串上
strong password in my iCloud
保存了刚才那个强密码
So, I don't know it.
但我不知道那个密码是什么
So, I'm completely stuck.
我卡在了这里
So, I go back to the web
于是我回到网络交互界面
interface, and I say I forgot my
说我忘记了
password.
密码
And I reset the password to
然后重设密码
something really easy like
设一个非常简单的 比如
Password.
Password
And now, I go in and I log in
现在我再去登录
and I've got no security.
完全没有安全可言
And I probably get hacked.
很可能就被黑了
It's a disaster.
会是一个灾难
So, starting with iOS 11, this
从 iOS 11 开始
nightmare is going to end.
这场噩梦要终结了
We are introducing a really
我们推出了一项
great new feature, where when we
非常棒的新特性
detect that you're showing a
当我们探测到你进入了一个
username and password field,
用户名和密码的输入界面
this key UI will appear in the
这个 key UI 就会
candidate bar.
在候选栏中出现
And if you click on it you get a
点击一下 你就会得到
list of all of your saved
所有你保存在 iCloud 钥匙串上的
passwords in the iCloud
密码的列表
And you can go through and
你就可以在列表中
select the right one.
找到正确的那个了
Now, that already is a better
这相比起刚才
experience than the one where
你卡住的场景来说
you're completely stuck.
已经是更好的用户体验
But it's not ideal.
但还不够理想
For a lot of users, they're not
对于很多用户来说
really going to know what to do
他们并不知道到底该如何使用
with this list.
这个列表
If you're like me, you have a
如果你像我一样
lot of passwords on this list.
那么你的列表就会有好多密码
And scrolling through it to find
滚动列表并找到
the right one might be a little
正确的密码 可能会
bit challenging.
有点困难
So, there's a way that you can
现在有一种方式
make an even better experience
你可以为用户提供
for your users, here.
更好的体验
Which is just a couple steps.
只需要几步就可以
So, we what we want is for the
我们需要的是
correct suggestion to appear in
在候选栏中默认出现
the candidate bar, by default.
正确的建议
And then, you don't even need to
这样一来 你甚至不需要
mess around with finding the
在一串列表中
right value in that list.
找到正确的那个了
And to do that, it's just two
要做到这一点 只需要两步
You have to add one entitlement
首先为你的 App 添加一个授权
to your application, and a
然后为你的 web service
couple of lines of JSON to your
添加几行 JSON
web service.
你为了支持通用链接
these steps to support universal
可能已经这样做过了
So, if you have done that, then
如果你完成了这件事
this really good UI will appear.
这个很棒的 UI 就会出现
And when I tap on it, I simply
我点击一下
get my password filled in.
密码就自动填好了
So, please for my sake, adopt
所以请看在我的面上
this in your apps.
在你们的 App 中使用这个 API 吧
We're really excited about it.
我们觉得它很棒
And go to the associated
明天也请去参加
session, tomorrow.
相关讲座
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
All right.
好的
There's a couple of improvements
接下来我想告诉大家
to Asset Catalogs that we're
对于 Asset Catalogs
excited to tell you about.
的一些改进
Colors can now be added to Asset
现在可以为 Asset Catalog
Catalogs, as well as icons.
添加色彩和图标了
So, you can now make named
你可以制作带名称的
colors.
色彩了
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And this allows you to easily
这可以让你在适合的设备上
support wide gamut colors on the
轻松支持全范围
appropriate devices.
色彩
So, you can create a wide gamut
你可以建立一个范围很宽的
color and add it to your Asset
色域 然后把它添加到
Catalog.
Asset Catalog 上
You can access it by name.
你可以通过名称获取它
And you can also, make a
你也可以在
fallback color to be used in the
不支持宽色域的设备上
sRGB Color Space for devices
在 sRGB Color Space 里面使用
that don't support wide gamut.
fallback 色彩
And you can now, do the same
你还可以对 App 图标
thing with your app icons.
做同样的事
So, app icons can now include
现在 App 图标可以使用
wide gamut colors, which will be
广色域色彩
displayed on devices that
可以被显示在支持
support the P3 Color Space.
P3 Color Space 的设备上
In addition, you may find that,
此外 你可能还发现了
well, at least it's true for
至少对某些 App 来说
certain apps, that the icons are
它们的图标就是
actually the largest aspect of
占据这个 App 的容量的
your app's footprint.
最大的一个因素了
And so, by incorporating them in
现在 把它们包含在
Asset Catalogs, we're now able
Asset Catalogs 里面 我们就能
to have them participate in the
让它们参与进
app thinning, which will
App 瘦身的进程
significantly lower your app's
这会显著降低你的 App 的
footprint.
占用空间
So, this is a really exciting
这是一个非常棒的改进
thing to adopt, and it will be
在以后它会被
adopted by default in new
以默认的形式加入
projects in iOS 11.
iOS 11 的新 project 里面
You can opt into it in existing
你也可以在现有的 project 里面
projects by adding a key to your
这样做 方法就是在 Info.plist 里
Info.plist.
添加一个 key
So, PDF-backed images.
接下来是支持 PDF 的图像
These are something that have
这个功能其实已经
been possible for a little
实现了一段时间了
But there's a new option when
但现在你在 Asset Catalog 中
you add an image to your Asset
添加图像时有了一个新选择
Catalog, that's PDF-backed.
就是支持 PDF 的图像
You're given the option to
你现在可以选择
preserve the vector data.
保存矢量数据了
So, this is new in iOS 11.
这是 iOS 11 的新特性
And it's a really powerful
这个特性真的
feature.
很厉害
If you click that box, the
你点击一下那个框
vector data will be shipped with
矢量数据就成为你的 App
your application.
的一部分了
Which, on the one hand, makes
这样一来 可能
your application a little bit
会让你的 App 变得更大一点
larger, because the vector data
因为矢量数据要
takes up some space.
占用一些空间
But on the other hand, will give
但另一方面
you the opportunity to scale
这让你能够测量
these images, which might be
这些图像 这会在
useful in a number of different
很多场景下
situations.
派上用场
So, one is, if you know that
比如 假设你知道
this particular image is going
这个特定图像
to be used at multiple sizes.
会以不同尺寸被调用
But that might be less obvious.
但那不太明显
So, one case is a symbolic glyph
比如一个符号
that should resize with dynamic
要随着 dynamic type 变动大小
type.
既然我们想到了
dynamic type, you should also be
dynamic type 那你也就应该
thinking about having glyphs
想到要让和字体一起出现的
that are appearing next to type
符号的大小也能
resize appropriately.
有合适的变动
Another case that's really not
另一个十分不明显的例子
obvious, is tab bar images.
就是 tap bar 图像
So, you're probably used to your
你也许已经习惯了
tab bar images appearing at just
tab bar 图像的尺寸
a single size.
是单一不变的
But there's a really great
但我们强烈建议
accessibility feature that we
你们的 App 去支持的
strongly recommend supporting,
一个新特性
that allows for user that have
就是要考虑到
turned their dynamic type size
那些把 dynamic type 尺寸调大的
up.
用户们
When they tap and hold on a tab
当他们点击并按住
bar image, a larger version
一个 tap bar 图像的时候
appears in the center of the
在屏幕中央的 Hud 里
screen in a Hud.
一个大图就会出现
And as you swipe your finger you
当你轻扫手指
can see different ones.
就会看到不同的图像
So, you can support this in your
你可以通过返回一个不同的图像
apps by returning a different
来自你的 App 里
image to use for this purpose.
实现这个功能
But if you use PDF-backed images
但如果你使用了支持 PDF 的图像
and preserve the vector data for
并保存了 tap bar 图像的矢量数据
your tab bar images, it will
那么它就会
just happen by default.
以默认形式出现了
So, we really recommend doing
所以我们强烈推荐采用它
that to increase the usability
增强你的 App 的易用性
of your app across all users.
让所有用户受益
All right.
好了
And the final topic that I want
我想说的最后一个主题
to discuss, is ProMotion.
就是 ProMotion
So, as you heard, on certain new
你们已经知道 在一些型号的
iPads we're increasing the
IPad 上面 我们增加了
refresh rate of the screen.
屏幕的刷新率
And you can find out what the
你可以在通过在 UIScreen 上
screen's refresh rate is on a
查询这一特性来
particular device, by querying
搞清楚某个设备的
this property on UIScreen.
屏幕刷新率
So, once you've queried it, what
那么 你查询之后
should you do with that
又该怎么利用这个
information?
信息呢
Well, it depends on what kind of
这取决于你在创造
app you're building.
哪一种 App
So, if you have a UIKit
如果是一个 UIKit App
application, the answer is
那么实际上你
actually you really shouldn't do
不该用这个特性
much with this.
做什么事
The crucial thing for a UIKit
对于 UIKit App 来说
application, is you just want to
最重要的事就是你只想
optimize your drawing code.
优化你的绘图代码
You just want to make sure that
你只需要保证
you're getting your frame rate
你的帧率
as high as you can on all
在所有设备上
devices.
越高越好
And to do that, we strongly
要做到这一点 我们强烈建议
recommend using Instruments.
使用 Instruments
You can check out the frame rate
你可以查看
that you're achieving during
在滚动和动画时
scrolling and animations.
所达到的帧率
And find out what might be
然后找到
bogging you down.
拖慢你的因素
And if you do that, then it will
如果你这样做了
really improve the user
就会加强你的 App
experience on your app across
在所有设备上的
all devices, including ones with
用户体验 包括那些
a higher screen refresh rate.
高屏幕刷新率的设备
The situation is more
这个情况对于
complicated for Metal apps.
Metal App 来说更复杂
So, for apps that are using
对于那些使用 Metal 的 App 来说
Metal, you're going to want to
你就要更多地考虑
think more about what refresh
在不同场景下
rates to try to hit in different
使用什么样的帧率
So, your goal here, is to ensure
你的目标就是保证
smooth playback.
流畅的播放
And in the past, you might have
在过去 你可能会
been actually pessimistically
悲观地
clamping your refresh rate to 30
把刷新率调低到
frames per second to make sure
每秒 30 帧 以保证
that the frame rate is smooth.
帧率的顺畅
But now, on devices that support
但现在 在支持
higher screen refresh rates, you
高刷新率的设备上
could, for example, clamp to 40
你可以把刷新率
frames per second to get a
上调到每秒 40 帧
better smooth playback
获得更加顺畅的体验
experience, since 40 divides
因为 40 可以被
evenly into 120 frames per
每秒 120 帧的帧率
second.
整除
If you're showing cinematic
如果你要展示电影视频内容
content, you might want to
你就可以选择
choose a refresh rate of 24
每秒 24 帧的刷新率
frames per second, which now
现在这个刷新率
also, will look really smooth on
在这些设备上也会显得
these devices.
非常顺畅了
So, a lot of options, here.
所以选择是很多的
You probably want to think about
你要根据你所展示的
the content that you're
内容来考虑
displaying to conserve power.
节能的问题
You don't want to be hitting 120
你不会想要一直保持
fps all the time.
120 帧的高帧率的
And finally, you can use XCode's
最后 你还可以用 XCode 的
GPU Report feature to look at
GPU Report 特性来查看
the performance characteristics
你的 Metal App 的
of your Metal applications.
性能特点
There is a session on
接下来会有一场
Introducing Metal 2, that we
介绍 Metal 2 的讲座
strongly recommend going to.
我们强烈建议大家去
And that's what's new.
这就是全部内容了
So, I'm going to hand it back
现在我要把舞台
over to Josh.
交给 Josh 了
Thanks, very much.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Eliza.
&gt;&gt; 多谢 Eliza
We got a late start, this
今天早晨我们开始的
morning.
有点晚
So, we're going to have a really
所以现在我们的结束语
quick end, right now.
就得抓紧了
I have one last topic I wanted
我要很快再介绍
to talk about, really quickly,
最后一个主题
and I promise this is really
我保证会非常快
quick.
本地化对于
way to broaden the reach of your
扩大你的 App 的应用范围来说无疑非常关键
And for many people,
对很多人来说
Localization can seem synonymous
本地化和翻译是
with translation.
同义词
But it's actually more than
但实际并非如此
And one quick thing I just want
所以我想提一句
to mention is considering
要考虑本地化 App 的
layouts that are important for
layout
localized applications.
这很重要
So, take a look at this, really
让我们抓紧时间看一下这个
For many of you, this probably
对很多人来说
feels really comfortable.
这也许看上去很舒服
But if you now, keep watching.
但如果继续看下去
I'm going to change it, and
我要做一些改变
hopefully, make you feel kind of
可能就会让你们
uncomfortable.
不舒服了
Now, this probably seems really
这个看上去是不是真的
backwards.
很差劲
Labels are aligned weird, arrows
标志怪怪的
are in the wrong direction,
箭头指错了方向
animations happen the wrong way.
动画也出错了
But believe it or not, this is
但信不信由你
actually a real layout.
这是一个真正的 layout
You just don't usually see it
我们只是不太会在英语 App 中
with English.
看到它
You usually see it with a
一般是会在从右向左的
language that reads right to
语言中见到这种情况
left, like Arabic or Hebrew.
比如阿拉伯语或希伯来语
Now, for a user that expects to
对于希望看到这些的用户来说
see this, this feels really
这才是自然的
So, if you felt comfortable with
如果你看到这个感觉舒服
this and uncomfortable with
看到这个感觉不舒服
Then, now you know what someone
那你就知道那些
whose native language reads
母语是从右向左的人们
right to left feels like if
如果他们看到这些的
they're not presented with this.
感受是什么样了
Now, you want to make sure if
现在你要保证
you're localizing, that you also
在本地化的同时
support RTL in your layouts, if
在 layoutI 里也要支持从右向左
you're going to support RTL
要支持从右向左的
languages.
语言
Because the system is doing this
因为系统各处
all over the place.
都是支持的
Many teams have been spending a
很多团队都花了大把时间
lot of time to make sure that
来保证这项特性
this is right.
运行正常
And in fact, UIKit does a lot of
实际上 UIKit 已经为你
it for you.
做了很多
So, navigation controllers and
导航控制和开关
switches will switch
都能自动开关
But if you're building your own
但如果你要设计
custom views, you definitely
定制的 view
want to take a look at your
那你一定要考虑到
layouts in RTL languages, as
从右向左语言的 layouts
well, if you localize in those
如果你要在使用这些语言的地方本地化
languages.
你的 App
So, that was my really quick
这就是我对于这件事的
wrap-up on that.
快速总结
Lots more information about
关于本地化
localization in the Localization
在 developer.apple.com 的本地化指南上
Guide on developer.apple.com.
还有很多信息
And of course, there's plenty
当然关于本场演讲
more info available from this
还有持续整周的
session, and a ton of related
大量演讲的信息
sessions, all week.
在网站上都会有
The four Drag and Drop sessions
关于拖拽与放置的四场演讲
are going to be great.
会非常精彩
You definitely should check them
大家一定不要错过
out.
为 iOS 11 升级你的 App
really going to be a great
这场演讲也会
session, as well.
非常精彩
And make Eliza happy and go
为了让 Eliza 高兴
check out the Introducing
大家也请去参加
Password Autofill for Your Apps.
介绍 Password Autofill 的演讲
And implement that.
并加以应用
Thanks, very much.
非常感谢大家
And enjoy the week.
祝大家本周开心度过  收获良多
[ Applause ]
[掌声]